when I started this YouTube channel four
years ago most react developers would
have laughed at the idea of using
something like typescript you should
you should nah bro like why would you
take your beautiful functional
JavaScript and bloat it with a bunch of
type definitions that make it look like
the real Jabba I was very skeptical of
it myself when I first started using it
in an angular project in 2017. now maybe
it's just the Stockholm syndrome talking
but after using it I've never wanted to
go back but I don't think I'm alone
because it was the second most loved
technology on the 2020 stack Overflow
survey in today's video you'll learn
everything you need to know to get
started with typescript and react but
more importantly we'll talk about why or
why not you should use it because
there's a good case to be made for both
sides of that argument if you're new
here like And subscribe and become a pro
member at fireship i o to get access to
my full next JS react course to decide
whether or not you want to use
typescript let's take a look at two
different projects side by side one with
typescript and one without there are
many different ways to add typescript to
a react app in this case I'm using the
create react app tool but specifying the
typescript template the docs also have
instructions for adding it to an
existing project or you can learn how to
set it up in next.js in my course if we
look at the file system on these two
projects side by side the most obvious
difference is that the typescript
project has files ending in dot TS or
dot TSX but the weird thing is that if
we look inside one of these files the
code is exactly the same as the
Javascript file and that actually brings
up a good question what is typescript if
my code is exactly the same typescript
as a language is a superset of
JavaScript that means vanilla JavaScript
is also 100 valid typescript in other
words it just adds extra optional
features on top of regular JavaScript
the relationship between scss and CSS is
the same as typescript and JavaScript
and that's really cool because it means
you don't really have to learn anything
to get started with it but here's the
catch browsers don't know how to run
typescript code what is this crap which
means that we need a compiler to take
our typescript code and transpile it or
compile it down to regular JavaScript in
our TS project you'll notice a special
file called tsconfig its purpose is to
customize the behavior of the compiler
which itself is able to take your
typescript code and convert it to any
flavor of JavaScript trip that you want
to run in the browser compilers are
really cool because they allow you to
use special features and modern
JavaScript syntax without having to
worry whether or not that code is going
to be supported on Old Legacy browsers
the drawback is that you now have this
giant configuration file to worry about
normally everything just works but when
it doesn't you have to Google all these
different options and figure out what
they do many of the options are related
to how strict typescript is with its
type checking rules and I'd highly
recommend making it as strict as
possible by putting strict mode to True
that'll make your code initially more
difficult to write but in the long run
it makes refactoring and collaborating
with other developers way easier another
important option is Target which is the
flavor of JavaScript that typescript
will compile your code to es5 is the
2009 version of JavaScript but your code
base can write 2021 JavaScript sounds
amazing but do you really need
typescript to do that under the hood the
JavaScript version of create react app
uses a compiler called Babel that does
the exact same thing so the bottom line
is that you can write modern code in
both a react.js or TS project now one
thing you'll often hear typescript
developers say is that it helps them
catch silly bugs in development before
they become huge disasters in production
let's take a look at an example to see
if that's true or not in the JavaScript
project I have some state that starts
off as an empty object now somewhere
else I might reference that object and
try to access a deeply nested property
on it that looks like valid code but
when we run the app we get an error that
it cannot read that property bugs like
this get shipped to production all the
time but if we try to do the same thing
in typescript it's like a goddamn precog
that lets us know the error exists
before the app even runs I really
appreciate that because I make silly
mistakes like that all the time but keep
in mind that it doesn't replace test
driven development it can detect poorly
structured code in advance but can't
detect batlogic but now let's look at
the most important feature of typescript
its type system and the pros and cons of
using it if we build a functional
component in JavaScript you'll notice
that it has a type of jsx element in
addition if we reference props they
automatically have a type of any that's
a pretty vague type definition overall
in typescript we can be much more
explicit about what our code actually is
react has a built-in type called FC
which stands for function component and
we can assign that type to the component
using a colon followed by the type that
tells the compiler the shape of this
code which will throw an error for
anything that's not a valid prop and
autocomplete everything else by default
the only known react prop is children
but we can Define the shape of our own
props using a typescript interface an
interface allows you to define the shape
of an object by matching a property name
to a type like here we have an interface
called cool props that should be an
object with two properties one of which
is a number and the other a string in
its current form the interface will make
these properties required on the object
but you can make them optional by adding
a question mark after the property name
we can now take this interface and pass
it to the function component type by
wrapping it in angle brackets this is
like saying we have a function component
that also includes props of its own
custom shape and now we get really
useful intellisense on any props when
working with this component and it also
guarantees that we use the required
props when working with this component
in jsx however that did come at a pretty
significant cost we've added a lot of
boilerplate to the code base without
adding any new functionality for the
user now it is possible to bypass type
checking whenever you want by simply
adding the any type that allows you to
opt out of typescript but also negates
all of its benefits it's also worth
noting that typescript can provide
automatic documentation for your code
because your editor will automatically
pick up the type definitions so anybody
using your code will get intellisense on
the shape and purpose of it and that's
way way more efficient than having to go
read some documentation online now in
many cases typescript can automatically
infer the type without you having to add
any additional code to the code base for
example you might want to strongly type
the use statehook however the angle
brackets may not be necessary here
because if you have a default value of a
string you don't need to give it an
explicit type it'll have a string type
automatically and if you try to change
it to a value that's not a string you'll
get that precog error in vs code so
that's pretty nice but is typescript
really worth it it's managed by
Microsoft Enterprise loves it but some
guy on the internet said it only catches
15 percent of bugs while Airbnb said it
catches 38 percent of bugs would you
rather write more code or would you
rather be more confident in the code you
do write would you rather look at your
documentation on a website or would you
rather have it be automatic in your
editor would you rather write faster
code now or deal with chaotic
refactoring later do your friends and
family love it or do they hate it these
are all trade-offs that you need to
think about but in my opinion the answer
to should you use typescript with react
is obviously