C++ a statically typed compiled
programming language famous for its
widespread use in software
infrastructure and Infamous for its
steep learning curve it was created in
1979 by bej Strauss at AT&T Bell Labs he
was inspired by the object-oriented
nature of simula but needed a language
with a high performance of c and thus C
with classes was born it's designed as a
suet of C which means that virtually any
c program is also a valid C++ program
but it also adds zero overhead
abstractions such as object-oriented
patterns like polymorphism encapsulation
and inheritance today it's used in a
wide variety of systems with constrained
memory demands like the Unreal Engine
for AAA video games programs like Adobe
After Effects that were used to edit
this video databases like MySQL and
mongodb embedded systems like the
display on your smart toaster and is
used to implement much of our low-level
infrastructure like language compilers
and virtual machines it's so popular
because it provides low-level memory and
Hardware control like C but with highle
abstractions like classes and Mark
pointers C++ makes it harder to shoot
yourself in the foot but when you do
it'll blow your whole leg off to get
started install a C+ plus compiler like
GCC or clang then create a file ending
in CPP include IO stream from the
standard library to handle input and
output your code will start executing
from the main function to print hello
world we simply use standard character
output followed by the bit y shift left
operator and a string literal we can get
rid of this STD though by adding a
namespace to the top of the file now if
we want to create a string variable we
can do so by typing it as an array of
characters however if we include string
from the standard Library we can use the
string type instead the real game
changer though is the fact that C++
supports object-oriented programming
with classes a class is just a blueprint
for an object inside a class you can
Define attributes and methods that will
be private by default or make them
public by adding them under the public
specifier it's also possible to Define
methods outside the class definition
using a double colon methods can also be
defined multiple times with different
parameters which is known as overloading
and is a form of polymorphism in
addition we can Define Constructors and
destructors to run code when an object
is created or destroy classes also
support inheritance allowing developers
to more efficiently share logic
throughout a program to instantiate an
object type the class name followed by
the name of your object and optionally
any parameters for the Constructor when
it comes to memory we could manage
everything manually with pointers and
references however tools like unique
pointer can get the job done in a way
that's easier and safer by ensuring that
only one object can be allocated to
memory now to run your code open up the
terminal and use a tool like clang ++ to
compile it this has been C++ in 100
seconds hit the like button and
subscribe if you want to see more short
videos like this thanks for watching and
I will see you in the next one