C A statically typed procedural
programming language famous for making
the world go around it's the language
behind many tools we take for granted
like the windows Linux and Mac operating
system kernels databases like MySQL
interpreters for languages like python
tools like vim and git and countless
others it was created in 1972 by Dennis
Richie at Bell Labs where it would be
used to develop the Unix operating
system it would go on to become the
mother of all languages inspiring the
syntax of C++ CP Java JavaScript Pearl
and PHP just to name a few it compiles
directly to machine code and requires
minimal runtime support but is platform
dependent meaning the executable is
designed to run on a specific operating
system it's a highlevel language
designed for humans yet provides
low-level control over memory and
Hardware there's no garbage collector
instead your code needs to manage its
own memory when you create a variable
it's assigned an address in memory you
can store that address in another
variable called a pointer when the
variable is no longer needed you'll need
to free it to avoid memory leaks to get
started install a c compiler a popular
choice is the g c compiler or GCC create
a file ending in. C include any
libraries you plan to use then add a
main function to it this is where your
program will start executing there's no
function keyword and notice how it
returns an integer type a return value
of zero means success while a return
value of one means failure there are
only a few basic types in C create a
variable by starting with a type
followed by a name and value use print F
to print the value to the standard
output or put an Amper standand in front
of it to reference its address in memory
there's no string type but instead Char
which represents a one by character
stored as an integer a string can be
created with an array of characters each
letter will have its own memory address
and be terminated by a null character
another approach is to start with a
pointer by adding a star character in
front of the type then we can allocate
four bytes to it now assign a character
to each index ending with the null
character to create a string when you no
longer need that memory allocated to
your program use free to release it back
to the computer's Ram the language is
procedural and does not support
objectoriented features although you can
create your own complex data types using
strs now compile your code to machine
instructions for your operating system
using the C compiler this has been the C
programming language in 100 seconds hit
the like button and subscribe if you
want to see more short videos like this
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next one